Irish Broadside Ballades BPP 1001
University of Notre Dame Rare Books & Special Collections
Irish Broadside Ballads
1790-1890
University of Notre Dame Rare Books & Special Collections
BPP 1001
2.7 Cubic Feet
Arrangement
Alphebetical by title.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of 559 broadsides, most measuring 28 x 11 1/2 cm. Broadsides were printed and sold in streets and at fairs and markets from the early days of printing, often by ballad singers. Many of the broadsides were printed in Dublin by P. Brereton, probably between 1860 and 1876.
Conditions Governing Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Songs--Irish; Ballads, Irish; Broadsides (notices)
- "The Aquital of Robert Kelly", 1860; BPP 1001-001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "The Admiral," "I'm a Gent," and "By the Sad Sea Waves", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "The Adventures of Jack O'Donohoe", undated; BPP 1001-003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "The Adventures of Roger O'Hare", 1868; BPP 1001-004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "A New Song on the American Beef and Austalian Mutton", undated; BPP 1001-005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "A New Song on the Amnesty Meeting in Tipperary Written by a Friend of the Cause", undated; BPP 1001-006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "A New Song Called Annie Lisle", undated; BPP 1001-007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The Anniversary of the Death Of The Irish Patriots W.P. Allen Larkin, Michael O'Brien. Monday, November the 23, God Save Ireland By D. Sullivan", 21 November 1868; BPP 1001-008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Answer to the Irish Emigrant," and "Long Long Ago", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "The Artificial Flower Maker," and "Plains of Waterloo", circa 1859-1866; BPP 1001-010 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "A New Song on the Attempt of the Life of the Very Rev. Father Ryan", 1860; BPP 1001-011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Song from the Backwoods", 1868; BPP 1001-012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "The Banks of Doon," and "The Bill Sticker", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-013 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Banks of the Dee", undated; BPP 1001-014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "A Much Admired Love Song Called the Banks of the Nile", undated; BPP 1001-015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Lines Written on the Barley Corn", undated; BPP 1001-016 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Bill Jones," and "I'm King of the Forest Glade" (1 of 2), circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-018 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Bill Jones," and "I'm King of the Forest Glade" (2 of 2), circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-019 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "Billy Byrne of Ballymanus", undated; BPP 1001-020 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "Billy O'Rorke", undated; BPP 1001-021 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Billy Pattison", undated; BPP 1001-022 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "A New Song Billy Pitt and The Union", December 1798; BPP 1001-023 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "The Bird Alone," and "The Emigrant's Farewell", undated; BPP 1001-024 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "A New Song on the Birth and Suffering of Our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ", 1860; BPP 1001-025 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "The Blackbird of Avondale; Or, the Arrest of Parnell", circa 1882; BPP 1001-026 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "Blow the Candle Out", 1870; BPP 1001-027 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "The Blind Boy," and "Come Home Father", circa 1859-1866; BPP 1001-028 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "A New Song Called The Bold Rake", undated; BPP 1001-029 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "Bonny Moor Hen", undated; BPP 1001-031 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "The Boys of Ballinamore", undated; BPP 1001-032 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "The Braes O'Gleniffer," and "Henry and Nancy, Or, The Lovers' Separation", undated; BPP 1001-033 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- "Brennan on the Moor.", undated; BPP 1001-034 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- "Bundle and Go," and "Donnely and Oliver", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-035 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "Lamentable Lines on the Burning of the 'Cospatrick'", 1875; BPP 1001-036 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- "Can of Spring Water", undated; BPP 1001-037 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Can Your Mother Pay Her Rent?", undated; BPP 1001-038 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "Calcutta House of Correction," and "The Boy in Blue", undated; BPP 1001-039 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "Campbell's Farewell to Ireland", 1869; BPP 1001-040 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "A Much Admired Song Called Carroline of Edinborough Town", undated; BPP 1001-041 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- "A New Song in Praise of The Catholic Church of Kantur", 1860; BPP 1001-042 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Champagne Charlie", 1867; BPP 1001-043 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "The Child's Dream," and "Fortunate Factory Girl", undated; BPP 1001-044 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "A New Song Called the Chimney Sweeper's Wedding", undated; BPP 1001-045 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- "Chow Bent Wedding," and "Single Young Man Lodger", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-046 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- "The Church Bill and Downfall of Bribery", undated; BPP 1001-047 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- "A New Song Called the Coast-guard on the Isle of France", undated; BPP 1001-048 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- "A New Song Called Coburn's Challenge To Heenan", undated; BPP 1001-049 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- "Colleen Dhas Crutha Na Mho", undated; BPP 1001-050 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- "The Collier Lads, Who Labor Underground", undated; BPP 1001-051 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- "Colonel Shea of the Irish Brigade", undated; BPP 1001-052 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- "Come Home to the Children and Me", undated; BPP 1001-053 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- "Condemned Men for the Phoenix Park Murders", 1882; BPP 1001-054 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- "The Constant Farmer's Son", undated; BPP 1001-055 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- "The Constant Lovers," and "Be Careful in Choosing A Wife", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-056 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- "Country Hirings," and "Will You Love Me Then as Now", undated; BPP 1001-057 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- "A New Song on the Beauties of the County Wicklow", undated; BPP 1001-058 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- "The Cow Eat the Piper," and "Young William of the Royal Wagon Train", 1882; BPP 1001-059 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- "Crafty London Apprentice Or, Bow Bells," and "Saucy Sailor Boy", circa 1863-1885; BPP 1001-060 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- "The Cruel Father, or, The affectionate Lover," and "The Boughleen Dhoun", undated; BPP 1001-061 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- "In the Days When I Was Hard Up," and "Up with the Standard of England", undated; BPP 1001-062 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- "A New Song Called the Dear and Darling Boy" (1 of 2), undated; BPP 1001-063 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- "A New Song Called the Dear and Darling Boy" (2 of 2), undated; BPP 1001-064 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- "Lamentable Lines, on the Death of Joseph McMahon who was Shot in Dorset-Street, on the 28th March '82", 1882; BPP 1001-065 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- "A Divine Poem Written on Saint Francis Founder of the Order of the Cord", undated; BPP 1001-066 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- "An Elegy on the Death of the Much Lamented Doctor D. M. O'Brien", undated; BPP 1001-067 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- "An Elegy on the Death of the Much Lamented Very Rev. Bishop McCabe. Air 'Exile of Erin'", undated; BPP 1001-068 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- "An Elegy on the Much Lamented Death of the Very Reverend Dr. Spratt. By Job Sadler", undated; BPP 1001-069 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- "Deeds of Napolean," "She Died for Love, and He For Glory," and "Moon is on the Waters", undated; BPP 1001-070 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- "The Disappointed Wife," and "Gilderoy", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-071 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- "Lines written on a Discussion, Between a Protestant Boy, and a Catholic Girl, near Dundalk, County Louth", undated; BPP 1001-072 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- "The Doting Old Man," and "My Father's Old Farm", undated; BPP 1001-073 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- "The Doctor Outwitted by the Black", 1860; BPP 1001-074 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- "Don't Be Angry Mother," "Massa's in the Cold, Cold Ground," and I am Not Angry", undated; BPP 1001-075 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- "Donald's Return to Glencoe", undated; BPP 1001-076 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- "Donnelly and Oliver", undated; BPP 1001-077 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- "Donny-Brook Fair," and "Lazy Society", circa 1855-1861; BPP 1001-078 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- "Down Among the Dead Men," and "The Englishman", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-079 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- "The Downfall of Garibaldi", undated; BPP 1001-080 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- "A Dream of General T.F. Burkes", undated; BPP 1001-081 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- "A Dream of General T.F. Burkes", circa 1860-1880; BPP 1001-082 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- "The Drunkard Reclaimed," and "The Dying Child", undated; BPP 1001-084 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- "The Drunkard's Catechism," "The Drunkard's Looking Glass," and "The Farewall to Folly", undated; BPP 1001-085 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- "A New Song on the Drunken Act", undated; BPP 1001-086 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- "Dublin Jack of All Trades", 1868; BPP 1001-087 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- "The Effects of Love," "I'm Lonely Since My Mother Died," and "London Agrah", circa 1859-1866; BPP 1001-088 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- "A new Song on 18s. A-Week", undated; BPP 1001-089 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- "A New Song Called the Emigrant's Farewell to Donegal", 1868; BPP 1001-090 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- "The Emigrant's Farewell to Ireland Air Burns Farewell", undated; BPP 1001-091 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- "My Emmets No More," and "Molly Bawn", undated; BPP 1001-092 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- "The English Courtship", undated; BPP 1001-093 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- "A New Song, Erin, To its Own Tune", June 1798; BPP 1001-094 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- "Erin's Green Linnet" (Copy 1), undated; BPP 1001-095 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- "Erin's Green Linnet" (Copy 2), undated; BPP 1001-096 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- "Evicted Farmer's Farewell", undated; BPP 1001-097 (Box 2, Folder 94)
- "Exile of Erin", undated; BPP 1001-098 (Box 2, Folder 95)
- "A New Song Called The Exiles' Return", 1868; BPP 1001-099 (Box 2, Folder 96)
- "Lines on the Expected Testimonial of His Grace the Late Much Lamented Most Reverend Doctor O'Connor Bishop of Saldis By Joseph Sadler", undated; BPP 1001-100 (Box 2, Folder 97)
- "A Song on the Expected Triumph of Sir Domnick Corrigan at the Coming Election Over the Tories", undated; BPP 1001-101 (Box 2, Folder 98)
- "Fairlop Fair," and "Albion the Pride of the Sea", circa 1863-1885; BPP 1001-102 (Box 2, Folder 99)
- "The Farmer's Boy", undated; BPP 1001-103 (Box 2, Folder 100)
- "A New Song on the Farmer's Tenant-Right", 1871; BPP 1001-104 (Box 2, Folder 101)
- "Lamentation on the Death of Father Carlon. Who was drowned at Bundoran, the 8th of July 1869", BPP 1001-105 (Box 2, Folder 102)
- "The Felon's Return to his Native Land", undated; BPP 1001-106 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- "A Much Admired Love Song Called the Feenian Lovers", undated; BPP 1001-107 (Box 2, Folder 104)
- "Fighting on the Rhine", 1871; BPP 1001-108 (Box 2, Folder 105)
- "The Fisherman's Daughter that Lives Over the Water," and "Meet me at the Lane", undated; BPP 1001-109 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- "Fontenoy", undated; BPP 1001-110 (Box 2, Folder 107)
- "The Gallant Farmers' Farewell to Ireland", undated; BPP 1001-111 (Box 2, Folder 108)
- "The Game of Cards", 1868; BPP 1001-112 (Box 2, Folder 109)
- "Garryowen", undated; BPP 1001-113 (Box 2, Folder 110)
- "A New Song Called The Gay Old Hag", undated; BPP 1001-114 (Box 2, Folder 111)
- "Hymn on the General Judgment Day", 1868; BPP 1001-115 (Box 2, Folder 112)
- "A New Song on the General Taxation of Our Days", undated; BPP 1001-116 (Box 2, Folder 113)
- "Gentle Jenny Gray," and "The Fashions of this Town", circa 1856-1890; BPP 1001-117 (Box 2, Folder 114)
- "A New Song Called the Girl I Left Behind Me", undated; BPP 1001-118 (Box 2, Folder 115)
- "The Girls of the Shire," and "The Oyster Girl", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-119 (Box 2, Folder 116)
- "The Glorious Meeting of Dublin Held in Cabra with an Account of the Bands and Banner Peace and Order of that Day For the Liberation of the Prisoner", undated; BPP 1001-120 (Box 2, Folder 117)
- "Glorious Sons of France", 1870; BPP 1001-121 (Box 2, Folder 118)
- "The Glorious Victory of John Morrissy," and Young and Single Sailor", circa 1853-1879; BPP 1001-122 (Box 2, Folder 119)
- "The Glorious Victory of Morrisey over the Russian Boy", 1869; BPP 1001-123 (Box 2, Folder 120)
- "The Glorious Victory of Richard Dowse MP for Derry City", 1868; BPP 1001-124 (Box 2, Folder 121)
- "A New Song in Praise of Gort-Town by Michael Shanahan", undated; BPP 1001-125 (Box 2, Folder 122)
- "Gosport Beach," and "Jolly Young Waterman", circa 1863-1885; BPP 1001-126 (Box 2, Folder 123)
- "The Grand Conversation On Napolean Arose", undated; BPP 1001-127 (Box 2, Folder 124)
- "The Grand Conversation On Napolean Arose," and "What's Old English Come To", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-128 (Box 2, Folder 125)
- "A New Song on the Grand Procession of Father Lavell on his Removal from Partry to Cong on the 16 of October, 1869", BPP 1001-129 (Box 2, Folder 126)
- "Grand Victory of Paddy Ryan, over Joe Goss, in America (For the Heavy Championship and 400, in Gold), 1880; BPP 1001-130 (Box 2, Folder 127)
- "My Grandmother's Chair", circa 1860; BPP 1001-131 (Box 2, Folder 128)
- "Great Fight Between Bendigo and Paddock," and "Remember the Glories of Brien the Brave", 1850; BPP 1001-132 (Box 2, Folder 129)
- "Lines on the Great Miracle of Our Holy Father the Pope", 1870; BPP 1001-133 (Box 2, Folder 130)
- "A New Song Called Grogan's Grove", undated; BPP 1001-134 (Box 2, Folder 131)
- "Hagerty's Ball", undated; BPP 1001-135 (Box 2, Folder 132)
- "A New Song Called the Hiring Day", undated; BPP 1001-137 (Box 2, Folder 133)
- "A New Song on the Hiring Fairs of Ulster", undated; BPP 1001-138 (Box 2, Folder 134)
- "A New Song on the Hiring of the Servants", undated; BPP 1001-139 (Box 2, Folder 135)
- "The Holy Missioners Farewell to Thomastown", undated; BPP 1001-140 (Box 2, Folder 136)
- "The Home Rule Man," and "Though Poor I'm a Gentleman Still", undated; BPP 1001-141 (Box 2, Folder 137)
- "Homeward Bound," and "Sally in our Alley", undated; BPP 1001-142 (Box 2, Folder 138)
- "Honest Working Man," and "Come, Landlord, Fill a Flowing Bowl", undated; BPP 1001-143 (Box 2, Folder 139)
- "I Vowed I Never Would Leave Her", circa 1829-1868; BPP 1001-144 (Box 2, Folder 140)
- "I Wish I Was Lying Alone", 1869; BPP 1001-145 (Box 2, Folder 141)
- "I've Got a Soft Place in my Head," and "A New Song One Thing and the Other", circa 1850-1873; BPP 1001-146 (Box 2, Folder 142)
- "A New Song on the Insanity and the Doings of The Poor Judge", circa 1878; BPP 1001-148 (Box 2, Folder 143)
- "The Irish Brigade," and "The Fenian Men", circa 1860; BPP 1001-149 (Box 2, Folder 144)
- "The Irish Girls My Darling", undated; BPP 1001-150 (Box 2, Folder 145)
- "A New Song on the Irish Harvesters' Triumph over the English", undated; BPP 1001-151 (Box 2, Folder 146)
- "The Irish Jaunting Car", undated; BPP 1001-152 (Box 2, Folder 147)
- "The Irish Rake", undated; BPP 1001-153 (Box 2, Folder 148)
- "The Irish Tenant Farmer's Lament from Eviction from his Native Home", undated; BPP 1001-154 (Box 2, Folder 149)
- "Isabella, the Barbar's Daughter," and "The Exile's Return", circa 1867; BPP 1001-155 (Box 2, Folder 150)
- "A New Song Called Jack, You Remember the Nuts", undated; BPP 1001-156 (Box 2, Folder 151)
- "The Jacket Green", 1868; BPP 1001-157 (Box 2, Folder 152)
- "A New Song Called Jig Light Sue", undated; BPP 1001-158 (Box 2, Folder 153)
- "John O'Dwyer-a-Glana", undated; BPP 1001-159 (Box 2, Folder 154)
- "The Adventures of John Manks and His Pockmarked Cat", undated; BPP 1001-160 (Box 2, Folder 155)
- "A New Song called John Morrissy Again in the Field? Who he is to fight on the 1st of November, 1864.", BPP 1001-161 (Box 3, Folder 156)
- "A New Song on the Judgment Delivered in Galway", undated; BPP 1001-162 (Box 3, Folder 157)
- "Just Before the Battle Mother", 1860; BPP 1001-163 (Box 3, Folder 158)
- "Kentish Fire", undated; BPP 1001-164 (Box 3, Folder 159)
- "The Kerryman's Rambles. To the County of Tipperary", undated; BPP 1001-165 (Box 3, Folder 160)
- "Kiss Me, Mother, Before I Die," and "I'm One of the Olden Time; or, Fifty Years Ago", undated; BPP 1001-166 (Box 3, Folder 161)
- "The Labouring Woman," and "Polly Won't You Try Me Oh!", undated; BPP 1001-167 (Box 3, Folder 162)
- "The Lady's Conversion to Catholicity", undated; BPP 1001-168 (Box 3, Folder 163)
- "A New Song Called the Lady's New Fashions or the Girls' Dress Caps", undated; BPP 1001-169 (Box 3, Folder 164)
- "The Lady's Petycoat", undated; BPP 1001-170 (Box 3, Folder 165)
- "A Much Admired Song Entitled Lannigan's Ball", undated; BPP 1001-171 (Box 3, Folder 166)
- "Lark in the Morning," and "Fanny Gray", circa 1855-1861; BPP 1001-172 (Box 3, Folder 167)
- "Lass of Glenshea," and "Betsey of Dundee", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-173 (Box 3, Folder 168)
- "A New Song on the Last Dublin Election. Composed by Joseph Saddler", 1870; BPP 1001-174 (Box 3, Folder 169)
- "Lines Written on the Late Melancholy Death of T.F. Meagher", 1867; BPP 1001-175 (Box 3, Folder 170)
- "The Lamentation of Laurence and Margret Shields who was Executed on the 27th Day of May in Tullamore Gaol for the Murder of Patrick Dunne", undated; BPP 1001-176 (Box 3, Folder 171)
- "Lines Written on the Liberation of Barrett", 1870; BPP 1001-177 (Box 3, Folder 172)
- "A New Song on the Liberation of Robert Kelly", 1878; BPP 1001-178 (Box 3, Folder 173)
- "The Lish Young Buy-A-Broom," and "The Bonnie Lassie's Answer", undated; BPP 1001-180 (Box 3, Folder 174)
- "The Loss of One Hero on the Plains of Waterloo", 1840; BPP 1001-181 (Box 3, Folder 175)
- "Love your Own Land", undated; BPP 1001-183 (Box 3, Folder 176)
- "A Much Admired Song Called the Lovely Maid of Williams Town", undated; BPP 1001-185 (Box 3, Folder 177)
- "A Much Admired Song Called the Lovers of Derry", 1868; BPP 1001-186 (Box 3, Folder 178)
- "A New Song Called the Loyal Lasses of Castlerea", undated; BPP 1001-187 (Box 3, Folder 179)
- "The Loyal Lovers", 1870; BPP 1001-188 (Box 3, Folder 180)
- "A New Song on Lucky Elopement", undated; BPP 1001-189 (Box 3, Folder 181)
- "McKenna's Dream", undated; BPP 1001-190 (Box 3, Folder 182)
- "A New Song Called the Maid of Ballymoat", undated; BPP 1001-191 (Box 3, Folder 183)
- "The Maid of BonClody", undated; BPP 1001-192 (Box 3, Folder 184)
- "The Maid of Lismore", 1868; BPP 1001-193 (Box 3, Folder 185)
- "Maid of Slievenamon", undated; BPP 1001-194 (Box 3, Folder 186)
- "Maid of Sweet Gurteen," and "Answer to Betsy of Ballintown Brae", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-195 (Box 3, Folder 187)
- "A New Song Called the Malisia Man", undated; BPP 1001-196 (Box 3, Folder 188)
- "[On board] Of The Man-of-war," and "Hurrah for the Road", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-197 (Box 3, Folder 189)
- "A New Song Called The Mantle So Green", undated; BPP 1001-198 (Box 3, Folder 190)
- "The Mantle So Green", undated; BPP 1001-199 (Box 3, Folder 191)
- "The Mantle So Green," and "The Open Sea's My Home", undated; BPP 1001-200 (Box 3, Folder 192)
- "My Bark is Bounding Near," "Maiden, I'll Never Deceive Thee," "Pirate Crew," "Standard Bearer," "Marble Halls," and "Love Not", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-201 (Box 3, Folder 193)
- "Mary Jane, Parody on Old Log Cabin down the Lane," "Out in the Moonlight," and "The Hat My Father Wore!", undated; BPP 1001-202 (Box 3, Folder 194)
- "Mary Melvin", undated; BPP 1001-203 (Box 3, Folder 195)
- "Meeting of Tara", undated; BPP 1001-204 (Box 3, Folder 196)
- "Merry Ploughboy," and "Old Soldier's Daughter", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-205 (Box 3, Folder 197)
- "The Minute-Gun at Sea," "The Keel Row," and "Harry Bluff", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-206 (Box 3, Folder 198)
- "Mitchell's Address", undated; BPP 1001-207 (Box 3, Folder 199)
- Cronan, Jeramiah, "Lines Written on the Most Dreadful Fire that Broke out in Chicago in America", 1871; BPP 1001-208 (Box 3, Folder 200)
- "A New Song Called Molly My Darling Don't Leave Me", undated; BPP 1001-209 (Box 3, Folder 201)
- "My Mother is a True Born Irishman," and "Travelling Tinker", circa 1850-1873; BPP 1001-210 (Box 3, Folder 202)
- "Mother, Mother, Let me Kiss Thee," and "After Dark", circa 1860-1869; BPP 1001-211 (Box 3, Folder 203)
- "A New Song in Praise of Mr. Tait and the Harbour Commissioners", 1860; BPP 1001-212 (Box 3, Folder 204)
- "Mrs. O'Donovan Rosia's Lament for her Husband", 1867; BPP 1001-213 (Box 3, Folder 205)
- "Murderous Outrage and Attack on the Tenant Farmers at Douvilla in the County of Cavan", undated; BPP 1001-214 (Box 3, Folder 206)
- "Murphy the Blighted Potatoes", undated; BPP 1001-215 (Box 3, Folder 207)
- "Murphy is Coming", 1868; BPP 1001-216 (Box 3, Folder 208)
- "O'Reilly from the Co. Cavan or the Phoenix of Erin's Green Isle", undated; BPP 1001-217 (Box 3, Folder 209)
- "The Old Bedstead," "The Noble 24th," and "Home Rule for Ireland", undated; BPP 1001-218 (Box 3, Folder 210)
- "Old Dog Tray," and "Good-bye, Sweetheart! Good-bye", circa 1856-1890; BPP 1001-219 (Box 3, Folder 211)
- "The Old Oak Tree", 1860; BPP 1001-220 (Box 3, Folder 212)
- "Oleon's Ashes" and "Come Dwell with Me", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-221 (Box 3, Folder 213)
- "One Suit Between Two" and "The Scarlet Flower", circa 1857-1877; BPP 1001-222 (Box 3, Folder 214)
- "The Organ Grinder", 1868; BPP 1001-223 (Box 3, Folder 215)
- Purnel, William, "Lines Written on our Patriotic Priest Father Thos. O'Mally", undated; BPP 1001-224 (Box 3, Folder 216)
- "Over the Garden Wall", undated; BPP 1001-225 (Box 3, Folder 217)
- "Oyster Girl," "If I Had A Thousand A Year," and "Ellen the Fair", circa 1855-1861; BPP 1001-226 (Box 3, Folder 218)
- "Oyster Shell Bonnet and Dandy Chignauns", 1868; BPP 1001-227 (Box 3, Folder 219)
- "The Paddington Coachman" and "Mary May", circas 1855-1861; BPP 1001-228 (Box 3, Folder 220)
- "Parody on Paddle Your Own Canoe", undated; BPP 1001-229 (Box 3, Folder 221)
- "New Version of Paddle Your Own Canoe by a Sailor in the City of Waterford", 1868; BPP 1001-230 (Box 3, Folder 222)
- "A New Song Called the Papist Ass", undated; BPP 1001-231 (Box 3, Folder 223)
- O'Brien, M. "A New Song Entitled Parnell's Progress through America", undated; BPP 1001-232 (Box 3, Folder 224)
- "Parson and Quaker," "Though Fortune Darkly Over Me Frowns," and "Silly Young Maid", circa 1855-1861; BPP 1001-233 (Box 3, Folder 225)
- "The Methodist Parson, or, Preaching for Bacon" and "When My Old Hat Was New", undated; BPP 1001-234 (Box 3, Folder 226)
- "Patrick Brady", undated; BPP 1001-235 (Box 3, Folder 227)
- "Patrick O'Neill", undated; BPP 1001-236 (Box 3, Folder 228)
- "Patrick Sheehan", undated; BPP 1001-237 (Box 3, Folder 229)
- "The Original Peeler and the Goat", undated; BPP 1001-238 (Box 3, Folder 230)
- "A Perfect Cure" and "When Bucks A-hunting Go!", circa 1863-1885; BPP 1001-239 (Box 3, Folder 231)
- "The Phillipstown Murder and the Conviction of Laurence and Margret Shields", undated; BPP 1001-240 (Box 3, Folder 232)
- "Pleasant Looking Wife", undated; BPP 1001-241 (Box 4, Folder 233)
- "The Poor Little Sweep", undated; BPP 1001-242 (Box 4, Folder 234)
- "Poor Tom", circa 1853-1879; BPP 1001-243 (Box 4, Folder 235)
- "A New Song Called the Poor Wanderer's Sighs and Grief on Parting His Native Land", undated; BPP 1001-244 (Box 4, Folder 236)
- "A Pound or a Penny" and "Is That Mother Bending Over Me. Tune-Mother's Warning", undated; BPP 1001-245 (Box 4, Folder 237)
- "The Praises of Limerick", 1868; BPP 1001-246 (Box 4, Folder 238)
- "A New Song Called the Pride of Ardagh Air the Lass of Gowry", 1867; BPP 1001-247 (Box 4, Folder 239)
- "A New Song Called the Queen of Love", undated; BPP 1001-248 (Box 4, Folder 240)
- "A New Song Called the Rake of Rathkeal", 1869; BPP 1001-249 (Box 4, Folder 241)
- "The Rattling Boys of Paddy's Land", 1860; BPP 1001-250 (Box 4, Folder 242)
- "A New Song Called the Red Haired Man's Wife", 1860; BPP 1001-251 (Box 4, Folder 243)
- "Lamentation of Rilley and Mary Campbell," and "Sailor Boy's Farewell to His Mother", undated; BPP 1001-252 (Box 4, Folder 244)
- "Reily from the Co. Kerry", 1870; BPP 1001-253 (Box 4, Folder 245)
- "A New Song on the Release of the Fenian Prisoners", circa 1867; BPP 1001-254 (Box 4, Folder 246)